gopal balachandran the CEO and cro at
icsa Lomar General Insurance joins us on
the show right now Mr balachandran great
to have you today on E now U you know I
want to talk about what you've seen in
terms of uh monthly growth up updates
because your gdpi growth has has been
always more than overall the other
private players but the growth for
August was a little below your own run
rate that of 16 to 20% U help us
understand why this dip and whether this
is just a one-off
oration good morning I think uh that's a
great question to ask I think uh if you
ask us I think what we always maintained
is uh insurance is relatively a
long-term growth uh opportunity and
therefore to that extent uh I think it
would be great to look at numbers more
on relatively longer periods uh while
monthly slash uh quarterly or annual
period growth rates are relevant but
ideally to look at the numbers will be
much more from a longer term perspective
and in that context when you look at
let's say for The General Insurance
Market over the last 24 years I think
the sector has compounded at uh roughly
at about 16% thereabout from an overall
Market perspective and within that I
think from an ICA Lombard standpoint our
approach to writing risk has been to
significantly Drive uh profitable growth
and that's why the point that you made
in terms of us at least when you look at
the current year for example I think we
have had a significant relative
outperform perance compared to the
overall uh industry numbers and that's
how we are always positioned largely
looked at driving profit pools and uh
within that obviously identified
segments which we think are viable from
an underwriting
standpoint right so could you give us a
number as to when is it that you will
get back to uh High Teens um and will
that happen in the second quarter so
honestly again let me put this in
context okay so if you look at let's say
for the month uh even if you look at on
a five month basis we had a growth of
almost about 17% or thereabout uh the
industry growth was roughly at about
between 10 to 11% so in that sense I
think we have had a significant
outperformance the point that I earlier
made our sense is I think this Market uh
when you look at it from a longer term
trajectory standpoint should continue to
exhibit that growth range of 15 to 20%
and what we have maintain at least when
we have talked to the market we have
said we should ideally continue to see
that 100 to 200 basis points out
performance from a revenue standpoint
but this of course is keeping in mind
how the industry responds in terms of
profitable outcomes uh as we speak the
industry seems to be looking better in
terms of the trajectory to improve
underwriting and in that context again
when you look at our own underwriting
numbers I think we have been able to
kind of pretty much be on track in terms
of what we have talked to the market
at right morning Mr balachandran uh
given that there's a market share gap
between the top players and your company
that's only narrowing I want to
understand what strategy you're using to
become a market leader in the segment is
it largely driven by health and
motor so again that's a great point I
think in terms of uh from an iard
standpoint effectively the USP that uh
works well in so far as the policy
holder interest is concerned are
multiple factors I think for example the
brand IC Lombard itself kind of
significantly resonates when it comes to
uh policy holder satisfaction and within
that I think in terms of some of the
core capabilities that we have largely
looked at driving is uh make significant
use of data and analytics to Advantage
uh We've significantly leveraged uh
technology as a means to drive
efficiency and uh satisfaction in so far
as the customers are concerned and
equally and more importantly I think
what we have largely put a lot of
emphasis on is uh claim service uh that
again significantly distinguishes us
from the rest of the market and in terms
of the segments where we have looked at
uh potentials for growth is clearly from
an aggregate standpoint it's motor its
uh health and of course the commercial
lines which typically wherein we offer
insurances to small/ Mid large
corporates uh those are the
opportunities that one sees but within
each of these broad three segments I
think we try to do a lot more
segmentation of various uh categories
and try and write r which are
contributing to our profitability growth
Outlook you know you recently
highlighted that the competition is
moderating specifically in the health
segment does that also mean that pricing
competition is also moderating and there
could be a scope perhaps for Price
hike so I think uh couple of factors to
it I think the point that when I talked
about in the context of Health was uh
largely in the field of corporate Group
Health because that was a segment which
had kind of significantly got quite
aggressive in terms of pricing in the
last uh several years but since the last
couple of years obviously the industry
could not sustain those levels of uh uh
outcome when it came to underwriting and
that's the reason now uh companies are
talking about possibly making a price
change from an overall Market
perspective again when you put that in
the context of isisa Lombard I think at
those times when the industry was
significantly elevated on or let's say
stressed on pricing I think obviously we
Cal ated growth and lost market share
and now that uh Market is starting to
look far more disciplined in terms of
underwriting again you would have seen
in the context of corporate health or
group health for IC Lombard we have
again had a significant relative
outperformance compared to the industry
numbers uh so that's being largely the
thought process that we have largely
driven try to look for time Cycles when
the market starts responding favorably
and therefore to that extent their focus
shifts lot more into customer service
where from an i Lombard standpoint as I
said we have had a relative Edge so
hence to answer your point definitely
again the segment looks positive from a
corporate Health standpoint but just
slightly digressing away from Health
again if you look at it in the context
of motor for example again we had seen
postco for almost about close to 2 three
years uh there was significant price
competition getting exhibited in the
market similar thought process is what
we had exhibited even on motor during
this period where we actually end up
ended up losing market share but now as
the market is starting to show some
signs of semblance I think we possibly
starting to see again outperformance for
isard in the context of the market
numbers okay fair enough and um you also
showcased the use of AI you launched
Elevate as a product in the health
segment tell us a little bit more about
the use of technology or any new
products in the
pipeline so technology for us has been a
great business in
I think uh whether you look at it in the
context of uh our sourcing of policies
or even when it comes to the experience
that the customer gets exhibited to in
terms of uh claim satisfaction and more
importantly also in terms of the way we
are organized ourselves in terms of our
internal processes and therefore to that
extent as I said technology is a key
enabler and that's one area where we
have obviously wanted to put a lot of
focus on and across areas I think we
have been able to kind of Leverage
significant efficiency and productivity
Improvement through the use of
Technology lers whether it is through AI
whether it is through robotic process
automation or whichever uh other aspects
of technology that we' have been able to
invest in uh but just on the point on uh
Elevate that you kind of refer to in the
context that's a that's a new product
offering that we launched about couple
of months back I think that the product
solution that we launched was clearly
kind of factoring in the feedback that
we got from customers Distributors and
other relevant stakeholders and
therefore when we kind of launched it
couple of months back I think clearly
over the last two months the uptick on
that particular solution has been quite
favorable and possibly early days again
we would obviously want to kind kind of
look at it over long periods but at
least the two months in in terms of when
you look at the retail health market
share for us which was largely overing
at slightly less than 3% in the last
couple of months I think possibly we
have been able to get a reasonable Delta
again in terms of jum in market share
but as I said obviously we will wait for
the solutions to play out but that's
something again a work in progress
Elevate is just one of them maybe over
the next couple of quarters I think we
would possibly end up launching a lot
more solutions when it come to a product
profile okay interesting and we'll await
to hear all of those good chatting with
you today thank you so much for taking
the time out thank you so much
thanks if you like this video then like
share and subscribe to ET now